I'll get candles and
my mom's lace tablecloth.
And since it's Rachel's birthday...
...I thought I'd poach a salmon.
What?
Question. Why do we always
have parties where you poach things?
You want to be on the food committee?
Question 2. Why do we always
have parties with committees?
Why can't we just get pizza
and beer and have fun?
I agree. Fancy parties are only fun
if you're fancy on the inside.
And I'm not sure we are.
You don't want it to be special?
Fine. You can throw
any kind of party you want.
Joey, they're not real!
I start miles beneath the surface
of these things. They're fake.
See?
Honk, honk!
Wow, it's like porno for clowns!
The One With Two Parties
Neither of Rachel's sisters can come.
I still have to invite Dylan
and Emma and Shannon Cooper.
No Shannon Cooper.
Why not her?
Because she....
She steals stuff.
Or maybe she doesn't and Joey slept
with her and never called her back.
Joey, that is horrible.
Hey, I liked her.
Maybe too much.
I don't know.
I guess I just got scared.
I'm sorry. I didn't know.
I didn't think anyone
would buy that. Okay!
Hi, honey.
How did it go?
It was the graduation from hell.
My cousin went to hell
on a football scholarship.
It's supposed to be a joyous occasion.
Nobody thought my sister
would graduate from college.
It's a testament to what a girl
from Long lsland will do for a Celica.
What happened?
My parents happened.
All they had to do was sit
in the same stadium, smile...
...and not talk about the divorce.
But no!
They got into a fight
during the commencement address.
Bishop Tutu actually
had to stop and shush them.
You know the good news?
I get to serve coffee
for the next eight hours.
I guess we don't invite her parents.
-How about just her mom?
-Why her mom?
Because I already invited her.
Did you ask Stacy Roth?
Can't invite her.
She also steals.
Here are the candles.
Where's the birthday cake?
We're not having birthday cake.
We're having birthday flan.
Excuse me?
It's a traditional
Mexican custard dessert.
That's nice.
Happy birthday, Rachel.
Here's some goo!
Dr. Greene!
Oh, my God!
It's Rachel's dad.
Why are you here?
The father can't see
the daughter on her birthday?
No, no, the father can.
But since I am the roommate,
I can tell you she's not here.
And I'll pass along the message.
Okay? So bye-bye.
You're having a party.
No, no, not a party.
Just a surprise gathering
of some people Rachel knows.
-This is Phoebe, Chandler and Joey.
-I'll never remember all that.
So what's the deal?
Rachel comes home, people pop out
and yell stuff? Is that it?
This isn't your first
surprise party, is it, sir?
Hi, Monica.
The Chinese menu guy.
Forgot the menus.
So basically, just a Chinese guy.
Dr. Greene, come with me.
We'll put your jacket on Rachel's bed.
All right.
That sounds like a two-person job.
Well, my goodness!
What was that?
Sandra, I thought you were Rachel.
We weren't ready for you yet.
-You thought I was Rachel?
-Yes, because you look so young.
And because you're both,
you know, white women.
Oh, I missed you kids.
Should I put my coat in the bedroom?
-No, I'll take that for you.
-Oh, well, thank you.
Such a gentleman.
Thank you.
It all looks so nice.
So festive. All the balloons.
Oh, the funniest thing happened
to me on the way here.
-I was driving
-That's great!
I can't wait to hear the rest,
but I have to go to the bathroom.
Hey, come with me.
-What?
-lt will be like we're gal pals.
You know, like at a restaurant.
It'll be fun! Come on.
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
Oh, my God!
Think. Think.
What would Jack and Chrissy do?
Okay, now that your coat
is safely in the bed
We can come back out
in the living room.
Joey and Chandler, it's time
you take Dr. Greene over to your place.
Yes, absolutely.
Why, again?
Because that's where
the party is, you goon!
-See, this is just the staging area.
-Right, it's the staging area.
This is clearly
in the wrong apartment.
All right, you guys are off
to party number one.
And you....
You are off to party number two.
All right, let's keep it moving,
let's keep it moving.
At least send some women to my party.
Okay, that's Ross. All right.
Okay, they're coming.
Thank you for such a wonderful dinner.
Thanks for being born.
Thank you for my beautiful earrings.
They're perfect.
I love you.
Now, you can exchange them
if you want, okay?
Now I love you even more.
Surprise!
Oh, my gosh!
Wow!
Oh, my God. Mom!
This is so great!
Happy birthday, sweetie.
You! I had no idea!
-Really?
-No, I knew.
All right.
There's food and drinks on the table.
Go across the hall.
Right now, Joey and Chandler's.
-Why?
-Just go.
Weird.
Surprise!
Happy birthday, sweet pea.
Daddy!
Both of them are here? Both of them?
Both of them are here?
Well, we could count again?
I can't believe this!
You know, this is ridiculous.
This is your birthday, your party.
Let's put them together.
If they can't deal with it, who cares?
-I do.
-That's who.
Are you gonna be okay?
I don't really have a choice.
I can look at the bright side.
I get two birthday parties
and two birthday cakes.
Well, actually...
...just one birthday flan.
It's a traditional
Mexican custard dessert.
Talk to Monica.
She's on the food committee.
Some girl just walked up to me
and said, "I want you, Dennis"...
...and stuck her tongue
down my throat.
I love this party!
-Quick volleyball question.
-Volleyball.
We set up a court in your room.
You didn't like
that gray lamp, did you?
A woman stuck her tongue down my throat.
I'm not even listening to you.
-Dennis!
-Okay, that's me.
Can you keep Dad occupied?
I'm gonna talk to Mom for a while.
Do you have any ideas
for any openers?
Stay clear of "I'm the guy
that's doing your daughter"...
...and you should be okay.
I want you to take a piece of paper
Here you go. And write down
your most embarrassing memory.
When you're not using the markers,
put the caps back on them...
... because they will dry out.
Hi, Dr. Greene.
So how's everything in the...
...vascular surgery...
...game?
It's not a game, Ross.
A woman died on my table today.
I'm sorry.
That's the good thing about my job.
All the dinosaurs on my table
are already dead.
Listen, I don't mean
to be a pain about this...
... but I've noticed some of you
are just placing them on.
You want to push the caps...
... until you hear them click.
Gunther!
Where you going?
I was sort of thinking about maybe
No! No, you can't go!
No, this is fun.
We're just starting.
Here's your marker.
If you want to go, just go.
She'll yell at me again.
All right, I can get you out.
What?
In a minute, I'll create a diversion.
When I do, walk quickly to the door
and don't look back.
-I think I need a drink.
-I'll get it for you.
-What do you want?
-Scotch.
I'll be back in 10 seconds with
your scotch on the rocks in a glass.
Neat!
Cool.
Neat, as in no rocks.
I know.
Hello, Ross!
Where have you been?
I have been in the bathroom.
Stay clear of the salmon mousse.
Scotch neat.
That's Rachel's father's drink.
Mine too. Isn't that neat?
Scotch neat.
Would you excuse me?
Where are you sneaking off to, mister?
I'm getting my cigarettes.
No.
What do you mean "no"?
See, because that's the staging area.
You go in there, it'll ruin
the whole illusion of the party.
Take your scotch back in there...
...and I will get
your cigarettes for you, sir.
-Get my glasses too.
-All righty-roo.
What a great moment to say that
for the first time.
Okay, the first person's
most embarrassing memory is...
... "Monica, your party sucks."
Very funny.
Oh, no! Did someone forget
to use a coaster?
What?
I don't see anything.
Great, I'm seeing water rings again.
Ross, whose glasses are those?
Mine.
You wear bifocals?
I have a condition apparently...
...that I require...
...two different sets of focals.
Do you know my husband
has glasses just like that?
Well, those are very popular frames.
Neil Sedaka wears them.
I hear you can get people out of here.
You didn't tell me
your boyfriend smokes.
Yeah, like a chimney.
Big smoker.
Big, big smoker.
In fact, I'm gonna go into the hallway
and fire up this bad boy.
Are you wearing my glasses?
Yes.
I was just warming up
the earpieces for you.
Thank you.
Is that one of my cigarettes?
Yes, it is. I was just
moistening the tip.
She's taking the trash out,
so I can get you out of here.
But it has to be now.
She'll be back any minute.
What about my friend?
Only the three of you.
Any more and she'll get suspicious.
-Let me just get my coat.
-There isn't time!
Just leave everything.
They'll take care of you next door.
Is it true they have beer?
Everything you've heard is true.
Could you guys please keep it down?
We're trying to start
a Boggle tournament.
You!
And you.
You're supposed to be at my party.
And Gunther!
What are you doing here?
Welcome to the fo
All right, I'm sorry.
But these people needed me.
They work hard all week.
It's Saturday night.
They deserve to have a little fun.
Go!
You know, my party is fun.
It's a little quieter,
less obvious sort of fun.
But if people would just
give it a chance, it's
-You want me to see a therapist?
-Sweetheart, you have a problem.
You've chosen a boyfriend
exactly like your father.
Okay, Mom, I'll make an appointment.
But right now, I gotta go.
I gotta go do a thing.
Did you know your mother
spent $1200 on bonsai trees?
I felt like Gulliver.
Daddy, I really want
to hear more about this...
...but I just have to do some stuff.
You work and you work
and you work at a marriage...
... but all he cares about
is his stupid boat.
You work and you work
and you work on a boat.
He always ridiculed my pottery classes.
And you sand it and varnish it.
But when all is said and done,
he still drinks out of the mugs.
One night of her yoga
and Bridges of Madison County....
-The scotch, the cigarettes....
- The bonsais and the Chihuahua....
I may have only been in therapy
for three weeks now but
What the hell does she want
with half a boat?
Okay, okay, you can be shirts
and I'll be skins.
I'll be skins!
How you holding up there, tiger?
Sorry. When my parents were getting
divorced, I got a lot of "tigers."
I got a lot of "champs,"
"chiefs," "sports."
I even got a "governor."
This is it, isn't it?
This is what my life will be like.
My mom there, my dad there.
Thanksgiving, Christmas.
She gets the house, he's in a condo
my sister will decorate with wicker.
How did you get through this?
I relied on a carefully
regimented program...
...of denial...
...and wetting the bed.
You know, I just
It's so weird.
I mean, I was in there just listening
to them bitch about each other.
All I kept thinking about
was the Fourth of July.
Because it reminded you of the way...
...our forefathers used
to bitch at each other?
It's just this thing.
Every year we would...
...go out on my dad's boat
and watch the fireworks.
Mom always hated it because
the ocean air made her hair all big.
My sister Jill would be
throwing up over the side...
...and Dad would be upset
because nobody helped.
And when we did help, he'd scream
at us for doing it wrong.
But then when the fireworks started,
everybody just shut up.
You know, and it'd get really cold.
And we'd all just sort of
smoosh under this one blanket.
It never occurred to anybody
to bring another one.
And now it's....
Yeah, I know.
Thanks for coming.
I hope you had fun.
All right, I'm hitting the road.
Now, I've left my 10 verbs
on the table.
Be sure and send me
that finished poem.
Okay, will do. Glad you came.
-I think I saw Rachel out in the hall.
-Let me go check.
Your mom wants to say goodbye.
Happy birthday, sweetie.
You drive safe.
What are you doing?
I'm getting ready
for the water skiing.
Okay, big hug. One more.
Come on!
How are you?
-Where are you going?
-To get my coat.
We'll get that for you.
All right, all right.
I can get my own coat.
Sorry, we're on a major flan high.
Oh, no. No, you're not
supposed to be here.
This is the staging area.
It's all wrong. You should leave.
You know, just get out.
Or perhaps you'd like
a creme de menthe.
I have to be heading
toward my chateau.
I guess we're going back
into the hallway again.
Thanks for coming, Mrs. Greene.
You take care.
Oh, you kids.
Well.
This is the best party
I've been to in years.
Thank you!
Okay, everybody,
it's time for flan!
Yep! Get ready
for the gelatinous fun.
Looks like that stuff you get
when you get an infection.
Okay, that's enough.
Okay, Rachel,
make a special flan wish.
Okay, I've got one.
Heads up!
Wow! Those things almost
never come true.